crf-usa.org 2017-06-06

# Website & Donor Privacy Policy - Constitutional Rights Foundation

Website & Donor Privacy Policy   
  
**What Our Policy Covers  
** This site is owned and operated by Constitutional Rights Foundation (“CRF” or “We”). We take your privacy seriously and understand the importance of safe and secure information. This policy statement describes how CRF may collect, use, and protect information provided to us on this website and by other means.  

**What Information CRF May Collect**  
We collect only the following information that you provide to us voluntarily: 

Basic Information Necessary For Use of Our Services. When you register to use the website, we collect your name, email address, and your online user ID and passcode. For teachers to be able to access PDF files of any lessons or other materials, we also collect the name of your school and the subject(s) you teach.

Automatic Information. When you visit a website, you automatically disclose certain information, such as your Internet Protocol (IP) address and the time of your visit. Our site, like many other sites, records this basic information.

Cookies. Cookies are pieces of information that are transferred to your computer from a web server. CRF collects aggregated site-visitation statistics using cookies, but our cookies do not contain any personally identifying information. You can set your Internet browser to notify you when you receive a new cookie or to refuse to accept cookies.

User Communications. When you contact CRF through this website, we retain a copy of your communication in order to properly respond to you and to improve our services.

**How and When We Use Your Information  
** The information we collect is used for administering our business activities. From time-to-time, we may contact you to request voluntary financial support of the Constitutional Rights Foundation, notify you of important changes to the website, or notify you about new services. In all cases, we will do our best to honor any user request not to receive such notifications.

**How We Protect Your Information  
** We are a nonprofit organization that does not sell advertising **([latest financial statements](http://www.crf-usa.org/about-constitutional-rights-foundation.html)**). We may share aggregate statistics about site usage with our business partners. However, we will not sell, rent, license, or provide your information to any third party without your permission or unless we are required to do so by judicial, legal, or other government proceeding.  

We take appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure, or destruction of information. Financial transactions are handled through the secure server of our shopping cart service. Your access to many services is passcode-protected. We advise that you do not disclose your passcode to anyone, and that you sign out at the end of your session on the website. **Privacy of Children**   
CRF is committed to protecting children’s online privacy and complies with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). Therefore, CRF does not collect personal information from children under 13. We encourage parents of children under 13 to regularly check and monitor their children's use of e-mail and other activities online. We also encourage parents to consider using parental control tools available from online service providers and software manufacturers. These tools may be used to prevent children from disclosing their name, address, and other personal information when using the Internet.

 **Consent**   
By using our website, you consent to the collection and use of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy.

 **Changes to Privacy Policy  
** If our Privacy Policy or procedures change, we will immediately post those changes on our website. Any such changes will be effective immediately upon being posted, unless otherwise stated in the change.  

**Contacting CRF  
** If you have any questions, comments, or concerns about this Privacy Policy, please email us at [crf@crf-usa.org](mailto:crf@crf-usa.org)  or send postal mail to:

> Constitutional Rights Foundation  
> Attn: Privacy Policy  
> 601 South Kingsley Drive   
> Los Angeles, California 90005

**Effective Date  
** This Privacy Policy is effective as of October 22, 2009.
